<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jorge Sepulveda</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jorge Sepulveda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making a blog for the third time</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/third-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/third-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;third-times-the-charm&#34;&gt;Third time&amp;rsquo;s the charm&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have begun my journey of making a blog for the third time. My previous attempts we&amp;rsquo;re unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-attempt&#34;&gt;The first attempt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My very first attempt was a simple site done with HTML and CSS. This must&amp;rsquo;ve been during high school for a class assignment and quickly forgot about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was moving from Texas to Phoenix, I found my old stash of hard drives and thought, &amp;ldquo;Hey, I should plug these in and cruise down memory lane!&amp;rdquo; It was perfect as I had found a great opportunity to procastinate packing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;third-times-the-charm&#34;&gt;Third time&amp;rsquo;s the charm&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have begun my journey of making a blog for the third time. My previous attempts we&amp;rsquo;re unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-attempt&#34;&gt;The first attempt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My very first attempt was a simple site done with HTML and CSS. This must&amp;rsquo;ve been during high school for a class assignment and quickly forgot about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was moving from Texas to Phoenix, I found my old stash of hard drives and thought, &amp;ldquo;Hey, I should plug these in and cruise down memory lane!&amp;rdquo; It was perfect as I had found a great opportunity to procastinate packing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the site and didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything, I just left it in the same flash drive&amp;hellip;which may have been lost by this point. Pour one out for the lost bits of my first website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;docker-ifying-the-second-attempt&#34;&gt;Docker-ifying the second attempt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime last year, I tried making the same thing with HTML and CSS and was pretty happy with the design. The color scheme of this site was similar to the CSS file I had written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know why but for some reason, I attempted to put the site in a docker container. I got the whole thing going but then I realized Github Pages won&amp;rsquo;t host it and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t looking to pay the 10-15 required dollars a month to host it elsewhere. Maintaining it didn&amp;rsquo;t sound too hard but laziness consumes me so I didn&amp;rsquo;t see myself committing to that. Remember: It pays to do research!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fast-forward-to-the-third-attempt&#34;&gt;Fast Forward to the third attempt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was browsing NetworkChuck&amp;rsquo;s videos and he made a tutorial with Hugo and Markdown. This was perfect for me as I use Markdown A TON and the maintenance would be updating a git submodule every once in a while. I followed his tutorial except for the Obsidian stuff, another tutorial on hosting a Hugo site to Github Pages and Voila!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nice terminal theme where I can post my markdown files and host it on Github Pages for the acceptable price of 0 dollars a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only modification I needed to make from hugo was this container size. It was only 800 ish pixels long so I removed that to make use of the screen&amp;rsquo;s real estate. Mobile friendly too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that&amp;rsquo;s next is to finally christen this site with a domain name. I have been paying for my name.dev for 3 years(funny how I was ok with paying for that but fuggedabout hosting fees)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think now is the time to learn how to slap my name on the interwebs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll share the link to the video I used for &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/dnE7c0ELEH8?feature=shared&#34;&gt;reference&lt;/a&gt;. If I can build a website, so can you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
